# ELIJAH SEGUN SANGOSANYA

#### < Fullstack Web Developer />

$oxed{M}$	sangosanyasegun@gmail.com
()	https://github.com/flamezbaba
0	Lagos Nigeria

A Full-Stack developer with over five years of real-world experience building web applications that match client needs. I am confident with the skills and talent that I had earned with my past working experience across different industries.

I have developed several web applications from scratch, at the same time, I used to work on clients existing projects as I have outstanding debugging skills.

I love my work, and that helps me deliver in a much professional way.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCES**

#### Full-Stack Engineer - Maris Knowledge App (Contract)

Sept 2022 - Present

- Developed a RESTful Api for the game using Laravel PHP and MySQL.
- Developed the web frontend with Vue.js v3 and state management handled with Pinia.
- Integrated Pusher.io for realtime broadcast from Laravel to Vue.js
- Integrated Multiple Payment channels; Paystack, Flutterwave and Apple Pay.
- Implemented Apple Store payment verification on the backend.
- Developed new user-facing features, Ensuring the technical feasibility of UI/UX designs and Optimising the application for maximum speed and scalability.

#### Software Engineer - AstraTech NG (Part-Time)

May 2020 - Present

- · Building and maintaining the company's website and an array of product offerings.
- · I lead the reformation of the engineering, hiring process and playbook of the company.
- Played a key role in merging designs and application code to the finished skinned and functioning product.
- Contribute to the improvement of documentation standards, tools, and processes.
- · Lead Facilitator of their training services.

#### Backend Developer - Fimiti Logistics (Contract)

Feb 2021 - Sept 2021

- · Develop and maintain backend systems and infrastructure for the logistics company's applications and services, ensuring scalability, security, and reliability.
- Collaborate with cross-functional teams to design, implement, and deploy new features and functionality, as well as troubleshoot and resolve issues.
- · Create and maintain APIs and integrations with third-party services and systems, such as payment gateways and shipping providers.
- Ensure data consistency, accuracy, and integrity across the logistics company's various databases and data warehouses.
- Stay up-to-date with emerging technologies and industry trends, and make recommendations for technology adoption and process improvement

#### Frontend Engineer - Apex Instant Exchange (Contract)

May 2020 - Oct 2020

- · Made a Single Page Application with React Router, Redux, and React Suspense, which also helped improve performance across the platform.
- Implemented fast and reliable data transformation and diffing mechanisms on the frontend for our data pipelines.
- Crafted a solid design system to enforce consistency across the application.
- Collaborating with designers to ensure designs were efficient and technically sound.
- Unit and end-to-end testing with cypress

Lead Engineer - Accelerar (Contract)

# August 2018 - Nov 2018

- · Led a team of 3 engineers to develop an Enterprise resource planning (ERP) web solution for Powdera Healthcare Products using Laravel, MySQL for backend and Vue.js, Vuex for frontend.
- Introduced and enforced a consistent coding style across the application.
- · Crafted a scalable component library that enforced accessibility and fluency across the application.
- Created Documentation and trained staffs on how to use the platform
- Collaborated closely with Product, Site Merchandising, Design, and fellow engineers to develop and iterate on the responsive site experience

### Fullstack Developer - SammyTech (Fulltime)

Jan 2016 - Feb 2017

Location: Ibadan, Nigeria

- · Identified and implemented dynamic web solutions in accordance to company standards and best practices
- Worked on a team to improve the performance of the dashboard by lazy loading assets, deferring API calls and introducing cursor-based pagination.
- Made ajax calls via Jquery and update DOM
- Developed RESTful Api for e-commerce using Laravel PHP and MySQL

## **Developer Internship - Experial Tech**

Feb 2014 - Dec 2015

Location: Lagos, Nigeria

- Worked closely with the team to rewrite legacy HTML4 code to HTML5, focused on responsiveness and web accessibility. Used CSS dynamic preprocessor
- Eliminated dead code which saved us about 20% the size of every page load.
- Assisted the development team in building 10+ wordpress sites
- Integrated tawk.to livechat to help customers reach out if they have any problems using the website.
- Built websites with Codelgniter PHP

### SKILLS

#### Frontend

HTML, CSS/SASS/LESS, Javascript, Typescript, React.js, Vue.js, Nuxt.js, Next.js, TailwindCSS, Styled Components, Framer Motions, GSAP, Three.js

#### **State Management**

Redux, Redux Toolkits, Vuex, Pinia

#### Backend

PHP, Laravel, Inertia JS, Node.js, Express.js,

#### **Testing Frameworks**

Jest, Mocha, Cypress, StoryBook, PHPUnit

# **Productivity**

Slack, Trello, Jira, Notion and more

# **DataBase**

MySQL, MongoDB, Firebase, GraphQL, Prisma

#### **Other Skills**

Effective communication

Team player

Strong problem solver

**Great Leadership** 

# EDUCATION

## The PolyTechnic Ibadan

Diploma. Computer Science 2014 - 2019

# LEADERSHIP

# **President Computer Science Department**

The PolyTechnic Ibadan 2018 - 2019

# Nigeria Computer Society (NCS)

Member Since 2018

# **Lead-Facilitator CodeX Program**

AstraTech NG 2016 - Present

# LANGUAGES

English (Professional)

Yoruba (Native)

### INTERESTS

Music

Video Games